you are not going to see another way of initial access
to really using the scanning tools for you all know, if you want to know about your enemy, you need to gather some information about the about your enemy right
if you are targeting an organization, you need to know about the organization, what services there are using, what ports there are using, what of the version of the service service and whether they are using any victim like easily targeted services like VPNs or 3-3-8-9 so in this video we are going to see another one of the
3-3-8-9 port that belongs to an RDP, so the port 21 belongs to the FTP, port 3-8-9 belongs to an RDP
RDP, so let's open any of the terminal, so if you see here R-3-3-8-9 there is a remote RDP connection has been available right, so we can connect through the RDP, so it was in the public facing application, so we can use this RDP connection to get into a machine, so that's the point, so in this
RDP here we can find the RDP has been open and here the RDP has been open, and okay, so let's get on to the practical, so I just created, I just installed one of the VM and I'm going to hack this VM using the RDP methods, so first of all,
if we need to log into the RDP, we need the username send password, so we'll be get clear about this video, let's be able to do one by one, okay, so I just created one of the user called, my username is AJOi, and my password will be passed, this is my username and password, okay, let's see, this is just typing here, blindly, let me go to the user ij, yeah,
so my password will be pass, okay, so I'm login to my user username, okay, so let's go to an exploit, okay, so for RDP brute forcing, I'm going to use a hydro, okay, so here is a hydro command, I'm going to use a hydro for the for the RDP brute force, okay, so the T will be let me explain the hydro command hydro dash, so if the first
option will be T, right, so if you go for a T, it's a task, okay, so we are going to target a only one target, okay, we are going to target a Windows machine, so it's a only one target, so the next one, so the next command will be one, we are going to target one, okay, right, see, we will be a verbose, verbose will be giving more additional informations, that's all, and if we'll be the, let's see that, yeah,
so when I use a name password is successfully found, we need to terminate decisions, right, so we'll be, we'll be seeing there, seeing this later, so dash L means a login name, and dash T means a password, okay, so let me give the login name as ij, so this is the test to dot txt, I just created one, that was file, sorry, one of the text to document like, let me give some more thing,
this is the file we are going to use for a brute force, okay, so the threat actors contain a lot of passwords in the file, I'll be, I'll be getting you how to take this password from the GitHub, so here you can find, I have created a small board list for doing a brute force, so let me do a brute force, okay, so let me do a brute force, and we will be, we'll go for a login, okay, so let me,
so now the attack has been started, so you can find, so it was attacking one by one, they use a name as a j, it was trying one by one, basically the brute force means, means like a trying one by one, use a name sent password, okay, so we have created a few passwords in the,
file, test dot txt, and we are going to try one by one, one by one, use a name and password, okay, so you can see it first you tried a j a, the first entry,
so the login was failed, okay, zero child, so the login was failed, and you tried the next entry, next line, so next the login was failed, and it tried one by one by one, and finally, if you see the last, so I can get a green line,
so a j, so RDB goes to be the username and password will be passed, okay, so we are successfully found the RDB section, in the same way, in the same way, the threat actors will using this, okay, in the same way, the threat actors will be using this, publicly available available RDP service, for a brute force, okay, they will be brute,
they will be brute forcing this kind of publicly accessible service, and they will be finding their username sent passwords, and they will be logging into their machine, so I will be giving, so how to login into, I will be giving a small example, how to login into the machine, so already we have found a username and password, this is the one I just created for my own, okay, so I'll be getting you how to take a big brute force like documents like login fields like username sent password,
so X3 RDP, there is a one tool called XPRDP, for Linux machine, so you can go for a user, user, user, a, j, a, y, and you can go for a password, so password, we know, we already brute force, PASS will be the password, and we need to give the host name, okay, so host name on an IP address, so my host name will be our IP address,
it will be the 192.160.18.10, so this is 10, Windows machine, so this is the Windows machine host name, which I create installed, okay, so let's 192.168.18.10, so let me enter, so now it was asking some certification, let me UI,
so now you can see, I got a clean connect, directly, right, I got a screen connect, I can able to control each and everything, okay, I can able to do anything here, okay, so I can go to the browser, okay, so this section will be logged out, okay, so I can go to the browser, I can do whatever I want, I can do, okay, I can do anything, okay, so this is the way, the threat actors will brute force the RDP,
they will be using this kind of X3 RDP, or any other tools, they will be logged into their machine directly, okay, so this is a very, very powerful method, the threat actors will be followed, you can do anything, you can go to anywhere, you can go to any, you can set anything you want, okay, so this is the another way, exploiting the remote services, so this, you need to be very, very careful, so if you are username and passwords are very weak,
if your password was weak, okay, the threat actors can able to easily enter into our organization, okay, so you can see how easy I get into the server, right, I just created a small, small,
word list, for a brute force, for my brute force, and I use the hydro tool, for a brute force, finally I got a username and password, I use the username and password, for login into the, login to the RDP, right, so it's a very, very easy method, and it's a very powerful method, the threat actor will be following, I will be giving a live example, so how the threat actor will be using the RDP,
so how we did the same with the threat actor will be using the hackers will be using, so RDP, ransomware, using RDP, so you can see RDP can be used by a ransomware attack, typically the port 3, 3, 8, 9, we already queried with the so done, 3, 3, 8, 9, so you can find everything here, 3, 3, 8, 9, remote desktop protocol, okay, so you can do,
do some brute forcing in that, and you can get the current shells, and you can directly log into the organization, this is the one of the way, okay, so here you can find a lot and a lot of ransomware, they will be using, so see here, RDP abuse prevents in 90% of the ransomware breaches, okay, so 90% of the ransomware breaches, it will be happened by the RDP, so if you see this, it's kill our ball, RDP, so ransomware delivery,
we were using RDP brute force attempt, okay, so how we did the brute forcing the similar way, the same way the threat actor will be doing the brute force attempt, they will get inside the machine, okay, so you will need to be very careful about that, okay, so the threat
is will be using RDP for a initial access, okay, so let's, I hope you have clear understanding about the RDP, so first of all, we just created one of the word list file to use for a brute force, and we use a hydro tool to brute force the RDP, and finally we got a username and password,
so next we use the X3 RDP to login into the username and login into the our Windows machine, right, so next we use the username and password to login into the Windows machine, right, so this is the same way, so you'll be using, you'll be exploiting the RDP in the public facing applications, okay, and instead of this IP, you'll be giving a, your target, your company, which company were targeting that IP, okay, so I hope,
I hope you have a clear understanding about this video, how the threat actors will be hijacking our brute forcing RDP and get into the access, we will, I will get into one more thing, there will be a brute force passwords and all draw Q.txt, 2024, so here is a word list, so this word list contain a lot and lot of passwords, okay, so you can see here,
it's a 133 MB, you will be getting 133 megabytes of passwords, megabytes of passwords, probably more than more than like, like, blacks and lags of passwords, so we'll be getting a re, you are using this file for a brute force, okay, so instead of giving the,
test to .txt, you can give the, RQ.txt, okay, very, very, very opening, okay, so here you can find a lot of username and password here, so there's some, it's uncountable, okay, many, many usernames and password, okay, so instead of,
we can, using the justice to file, I'll be using the RQ.txt, so if I need to brute force, this kind of public facing applications, okay, so be very careful, the threat actors will be using RDP for initial access, so your username and passwords will be very strong, so if your, if your service RDP service is publicly accessible, okay, so your RDP username and passwords will be very strong, if you're using the,
RDP in a publicly accessible, next thing, so if you don't want RDP for publicly accessible, you need to restrict that protocol, you need to block that protocol, so preventing this kind of attack, if there is no RDP in their company environment, so the threat actor can't able to attack the,
RDP, they can't able to brute force the RDP, they can't able to get into, get inside the organization through the RDP, okay, so the first recommendation to be, so user, very good passwords, so that will be unknown by the threat actors, and the next one, so restrict the RDP and the final recommendation, if you have, if you can able to enable the multi-factor authentication, like your two way authentication,
like by, by, by, authenticating through the mobile, so some more DPP will be sent into the mobile like that, so go for that, okay, these are the recommendations, you need to provide to the customers, okay, so I hope you have a clear understanding about the RDP control, so how we, how we got the, how we got the RDP, so I can able to control each and everything in this machine, okay, so let's hop off this video and we will continue our,
we will continue our discussion in that next video, see you guys, bye bye, if you have any questions, any queries, just ping in a comment.